<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Geekodour's Blog</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://geekodour.github.io/</id><updated>2017-03-13T10:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>I attended KDE Conference 2017, IIT Guwahati</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/i-attended-kde-conference-2017-iit-guwahati.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-13T10:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-03-13T10:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2017-03-13:/i-attended-kde-conference-2017-iit-guwahati.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I attended the kde conference (conf.kde.in) 2017, it was my first ever opensource meetup or might even say first conference ever. I met people who are talented beyond my imagination, I loved the kde community and will be contributing to kde. Also, made a lot of new friends …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I attended the kde conference (conf.kde.in) 2017, it was my first ever opensource meetup or might even say first conference ever. I met people who are talented beyond my imagination, I loved the kde community and will be contributing to kde. Also, made a lot of new friends. This is my first proper step towards open source, also I came to know about GSoC, and Season of KDE. I'll try participating in every conference and event from now on and also send patches and contributions to many opensource projects. I love opensource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank Pradeepto, Wrishiraj, Rahul, Sinny, Srijan, Sunit, Pranav(I would love to call him Puri, Pranav and Suri), Tony, Garvit, and everybody else. It's been real. 
Thankyou! lots of love.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Some random sober thoughts</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/some-random-sober-thoughts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-11T20:45:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-11T20:45:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2017-02-11:/some-random-sober-thoughts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We humans are stupid, we're letting ourselves to be manipulated by this pathetic thing called life. We don't even know what it is really, but humans decided to call it "life" which otherwise in my mothertoungue (i am bad at spellings, so i don't know if i spelled that right …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We humans are stupid, we're letting ourselves to be manipulated by this pathetic thing called life. We don't even know what it is really, but humans decided to call it "life" which otherwise in my mothertoungue (i am bad at spellings, so i don't know if i spelled that right) is called "Jibon".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;So what is life?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this micro example, I am talking universe and macro here so this example which might be a huge one in our life can be considered a micro example.
Example: The Education System, I don't know much about other education systems but Indian education system sucks and the society supporting the wrong sides of this system can suck my dick. I am grateful for whatever I've learned but I have serious issues with the system, which I will make some big change someday.
So sing with me, "The Indian Education System Sucks". Maybe we can talk about the education system in depth in another blog post but we were talking about life, what is life.
So, take a example of two boys,
        - Was born in an isolated place, didn't know what education was, he learnt whatever he learnt from seeing things and other people
        - Now this is another guy, who had someone who put him into school and ultimately the education system and he became something that he would not have if he did not get the education(education here can mean, sports, music, academia)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there is this system which people can follow or not follow. The second one is a safer and smarter bet definetly and I really think NO one should be deprived from education.
The point I am trying to make is, you can be a part of a system or else you can't be, but everything does not have to be 1s and 0s like in computerscience. In the deeper level it might even be, but according to a video I saw today everything in the universe is made up of 12 quantum particles and 4 different patterns (Now I am not physics genius, I don't even remember the G equation, but ya that's what the video says), it says things are random and universe is made up of randomness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So back to the boys example, the first boy deprived of education can still get some education in some way or the other even if he was deprived of it. It's not a complete ON or OFF.
The guy working at some MNC still can be deeply related to some cause related to the uplifment of the poor. So a human can and actually living in two different worlds, worlds are just state of mind. His mind has to think differently at work and when he's thinking about the poor. If his mind stays elsewhere, then he's unconcious and can be knocked down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that's living in different worlds "inside" our minds. What about our physical bodies? What's life?
I think, life is a world just like that. You know, people persuade you to use their product, life fucking microsoft almost got me there when I thought microsoft was everything I'll ever needand it is still dominating the market and it's a good thing, but If I never discovered linux I would never have known the goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, life is probably just a product of category "world", "world" can be compared with "operating systems" where you get all the environment supporting the "zen and principles" of the operating system itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let's say we're tiny robots and we ourselves installed "life - edition Human with no disablities" which is an operating system in the us, we probably thought "life" would be a good one because we see everything live, it might be the best choice. The architecture(or probably i sould say working) of "life" is different from operating systems that we see today.
It does not make changes inside you, but it makes changes to the things outside you. Let me say that again,
It plays your mind, if the sun looks grey because you installed "life" it looks red to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what happens when we die? OS crash.
Blackout, no afterlife but back to our default state. We think life was a good os, can I use it again with myself? Probably I will use "huluga" this time, it will be nice to see and pass through each others bodies and WOW "hugula" was an new feature where the "world" can talk and communicate with people of other planet. I'll install "huluga" and probaly send an suggestion to life "Hey guys at life, you guys have a great world but it would be fun if you guys can add the feature to talk to other people of other planet".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guys at life be like, Okay. The upgradation will be done gradually, it must support legasy users of this OS. So, we'll just send patches time to time in form of "ideas and computation" which the users of life can make develop on their own to implemet the feature. We work that way at life. It would probably take some time.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>When you write code that is better than your previous code, It feels much better</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/when-you-write-code-that-is-better-than-your-previous-code-it-feels-much-better.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-31T18:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-12-31T18:04:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2016-12-31:/when-you-write-code-that-is-better-than-your-previous-code-it-feels-much-better.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I was working on this NLP project for sometime, today I am refactoring my code. The refactoring process is actally buring down all of my previous code and starting new. This time I did not do many mistakes that I did when I wrote it for the first time …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I was working on this NLP project for sometime, today I am refactoring my code. The refactoring process is actally buring down all of my previous code and starting new. This time I did not do many mistakes that I did when I wrote it for the first time. It feels good.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>I am hoping to complete the nlp project today, no celebrations</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/i-am-hoping-to-complete-the-nlp-project-today-no-celebrations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-31T14:10:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-12-31T14:10:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2016-12-31:/i-am-hoping-to-complete-the-nlp-project-today-no-celebrations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Things are taking some motion, I think I'll be able to make it happen. I sent an email informing my inability to go for a trip with my friends, All I can hope is that they will not hate me for this, zero emotions is something that helps me, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Things are taking some motion, I think I'll be able to make it happen. I sent an email informing my inability to go for a trip with my friends, All I can hope is that they will not hate me for this, zero emotions is something that helps me, and that's something I think is they way for me to be happy with myself, because in the end, it will be only me.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Why being alone is the best thing you can do</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/why-being-alone-is-the-best-thing-you-can-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T23:55:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-12-30T23:55:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2016-12-30:/why-being-alone-is-the-best-thing-you-can-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have friends, but I enjoy being alone, I feel comfortable, I can be me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't live in uncomfortable situations. A small defect or mishap in anything bothers my mind to a huge degree for some reason. So it's best for me to keep myself away from the randomness …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have friends, but I enjoy being alone, I feel comfortable, I can be me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't live in uncomfortable situations. A small defect or mishap in anything bothers my mind to a huge degree for some reason. So it's best for me to keep myself away from the randomness of the outer universe, and just try living in my own universe that is truly mine and no one can take it away from me, over which I have full control, i have to have that control. I need to live and be happy about living else rather be dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i am stressed&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>My First Post</title><link href="https://geekodour.github.io/my-first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T23:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-12-30T23:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Hrishikesh</name></author><id>tag:geekodour.github.io,2016-12-30:/my-first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nothing much.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nothing much.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>